Guide to the Eyes of Texas television show episodes and summaries collection, 1978-2009 MS 170
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- 1983 episodes, 226978
  - April 2, 1983: Bluebirds' Circle Clinic, Houston / Old Fire Truck, Orange / James River, Mason County / Happy Jazz Band, San Antonio 10/79 / Allen House, Marshall, 227002 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 188)
  - April 9, 1983: Student Film-San Jacinto, Plano / Ottine, Gonzales County / Whitehead Museum, Del Rio 9-78 / Bobby Friedrich-Metal Artist, Columbus / Bassett Bank Building, Brenham, 227001 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 189)
  - April 16, 1983: Bean - Dinosaur Gardens, Moscow / "Vieroy's Palace", San Elizario / Snider - Sandstone Artist, Argyle / Crow - Casis Elementary School / Tate-Seftenberg Brandon House, Columbus, 227000 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 190)
  - April 23, 1983: Byrd, Tarwater, Boley - Chocolate Truffles, Fort Worth / Witt, Bell, Pape, Browne - Warm Springs Rehab Hospital, Conzales / Gilbreath - Powellbuilding, Gatesville / Grassyville Cemetery, Paige / Santa Ana Wildlife Refuge, 226999 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 191)
  - April 20, 1983: Antonelli's River Inn Root Beer Stand, Freeport / Dubina, TX / Cabiniss - Iron Man of Salado / Smith, Smith, Baird, Potter - Possum Museum, Phonesboro / Houston, McCrocklin - Sam Houston Log Cabin, Independence, 226998 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 192)
  - May 7, 1983: Hamos, Allen, Chambers - Robotics, Dallas / Jaegars', Hochheim, Dewitt Co. / Middleton Water Wells, Marble Falls / Schreiner - Hill Country Museum, Kerrville / Texas Country Roads, 226997 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 193)
  - May 14, 1983: Grove Drug Store, Austin / A.C. Parsons-TX Safari, Clifton / Warren Plantation, Lake Jackson / Lutcher Mem. Presbyterian, Orange / Battle Adobe Walls, Hutchinson Co., 226996 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 194)
  - May 21, 1983: Carter-Newswoman-Alto Herald / Dalby-Tyler House Restaurant, Salado / Chili Cookoff, Terlingua / Bert Wilson-Old House Plantation, Richmond / Sea Rim Airboat Tour, Jefferson Co.-1980, 226995 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 195)
  - May 28, 1983: Ben Robertson-Drifter, Burnet / Hebbronville, Jim Hogg County / Geo. Younkin-Indian Expert, Arlington / 1917 Hanger 9, San Antonio, 226994 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 196)
  - Sep. 24, 1983: I-10 Complete to Fort Stockton / Raleigh House, Ingram / John Jackson- Basketmaker, Punkin / Prairie Box House, Cresson, 226993 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 200)
  - Oct. 1, 1983: Chimney Creek Ranch, Albany / Monterrey Square, Wharton / V&V Sausage(Vinklarek), Cistern / Big Thicket Bus Tour, Livingston, 226992 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 201)
  - Oct. 8, 1983: Kridler Gardens, Mt. Pleasant / Miss Hatties, San Angelo / Lester Oldfield- Model Ships, Houston / Cowboy Artist Museum, Kerrville, 226991 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 202)
  - Oct. 15, 1983: Bipes (Reptile), Texas A&M / Texas History Studies, Odessa / Dr Stevens Geology Trip, Terlingua / Bigfoot Wallace Museum, Bigfoot, 226990 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 203)
  - Oct. 22, 1983: Warren Home Building Class, Lake Jackson / Thornfield Mansion, Paint Rock / C & D Hill Woodcarvers, Toledo Bend / O. Henry Museum, Austin, 226989 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 204)
  - Oct. 29, 1983: Mo Ranch Hiking Trail, Hunt / B. Holster-Fiberglass Artist, Clarksville / Bank of Navasota / Horchow-Catalog King, Dallas / Loyal Valley, Mason County, 226988 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 205)
  - Nov. 5, 1983: YO Ranch-Photo School, Kerrville / White-Pool House Restoration, Odessa / James Mitchner, Austin / Baptist Museum, Independence, 226987 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 206)
  - Nov. 12, 1983: Verticle Windmill, College Station / Weimar Hotel, Weimar / Durell Roth- Antique Radios, Houston / Ed Knutz-UTPB Prof, Odessa, 226986 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 207)
  - Nov. 19, 1983: Oatmeal TX-Not on the Map / Joe Jones-Waller Creek, Austin / Kindergarden Rodeo, Coahoma / Brown Center-Lamar U, Orange, 226985 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 208)
  - Nov. 26, 1983: Texas Wine Tasting, Greune / Dr. Joe Shepperd, Burnet / Sydney Island, Bridge City / Buck Turman-Storyteller, Fowlerton / Parlor Restaurant, New Ulm, 226984 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 209)
  - Baskerville Reg Title Shadow 32p: Zollner's Hobo Haven, Fate / John Nation-Mud Artist, Lufkin / Giles Tippette-Novelist, Mason / Ashton Villa, Galveston, 226983 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 210)
  - Dec. 10, 1983: Jim Head-Yahoo Cakes, Rockwall / Lions Club Carnival, Orange / Jimmie Rodgers Jubilee, Kerrville / San Angelo Gardens, 226982 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 211)
  - Dec. 17, 1983: Texas Studio, Fredericksburg / Menu King, Eastland / The Cottage Christmas Store, Jasper / Clock Man, Scheibel, Galveston / Elm Street Historic Dist., Georgetown, 226981 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 212)
  - Dec. 24, 1983: Junk Auction, Kirbyville / Emma Seelye, houston / Craft Couple, Richmond / Indian Cliffs Ranch, El Paso / St Louis Church, Castroville, 226980 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 213)
  - Dec. 31, 1983: Clegg Cold Storage / Paul Boesch - Wrestling Promoter, Houston / Jackson-Hustmyre House, Orange / Honey Creek Ranch, Boerne, 226979 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 214)
- 1984 episodes, 226944
  - KPRC's summary of 1984 episodes, 226977 (Folder 7)
  - Jan. 7, 1984: Sesquicentennial Fashion, Sugar Land / Withers Place, Cairo Springs / Camp Swift, Bastrop / Crowe's Nest Farm, Manor, 226976 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 215)
  - Jan. 14, 1984: Old Town Spring / Moses (Toliver), Matagorda / Joseph Melancon-Prop Maker, Dallas / Treaty Oak, Austin, 226975 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 216)
  - Jan. 21, 1984: Jimmy King-Candy Man, Huntsville / OP Schnable-No Litter, San Antonio / Froehlich's Hardware, Rose Hill / Hall Of State, Dallas / Sacred Gardens, New Waverly, 226974 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 217)
  - Jan. 28, 1984: Tomkins, Dolan, Harmon - Sports Medicine Ctr, Tomball / Kandra-Soft Sculpture, Hitchcock / Jack Johnson-Heavywt Champ, Galveston / Longhorn Collection, Big Spring, 226973 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 218)
  - Feb. 4, 1984: Bellows - Blacksmith, Frederickburg /Keohan, Petty - RV TV's, Big Spring / Rep Rio Grande Museum, Laredo / Margit Ilika-Artist, Somerville / John Neely Bryan-Log Cabin, Dallas, 226972 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 219)
  - Feb. 11, 1984: Traders Village, Grand Prairie / Hungerford, Texas / Frank Brown House, Friendswood / L Krauze-Glass Art, San Antonio / Stanton Jail - 1908, 226971 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 220)
  - Feb. 18, 1984: Ponder Boot Company, Ponder / Our Lady of Mercy Academy, Stanton / Buck Schiwetz Tribute / Hickey Grist Mill / Japanese Garden, Fort Worth, 226970 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 221)
  - Feb. 25, 1984: Millhollen House, Stanton / Jess Shryack-Antique Plane/Cars, Justin / Ponder Cafes, Ponder / Slim Singletown-Windmills, San Angelo / Harmony Hill, East Texas, 226969 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 222)
  - March 3, 1984: Texas Tourist Center, Harlingen / R. Wilkinson, Guitar Maker, Ponder / Egg Brothers Hardware, Meyersville / Half Moon Lighthouse, Port Lavaca / Campbell Log Cabin, Seguin, 226968 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 223)
  - March 10, 1984: Depot Discovery Ctr., Henderson / American Cowboy Exhibit, San Antonio / Dr. Rivas-McAllen Mountain Climber / Gulf Prairie Cemetery / Thanksgiving Square, Dallas, 226967 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 224)
  - March 17, 1984: Rogers & Son Store, Stewart / Windsor - Roseland Plantation, Tyler / Thomas Morgan-RR Fanatic, Calliham / Santa Fe Trail, Ray Miller narration / Brown-Dorsey House, Midland, 226966 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 225)
  - March 24, 1984: James Galway-Flutist, Hill Country / Lone Star-Sailboat - Part 1 / Lone Star-Sailboat - Part 2 / Fort Croghan, Burnet, 226965 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 226)
  - March 31, 1984: Hefley Goat Dairy Farm, Hungerford / The Grove, Texas / Monkey Ranch, Laredo (3-29-80) / Chicken Farm Art Center, San Angelo / Patio of States, San Antonio, 226964 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 227)
  - April 7, 1984: Don Carlo & Annie-Magic Shop, Plano / Joe Paul-Peach Pit Carver, Oyster Creek / Madison Cooper, Waco / Davis Log Cabin, Livingston, 226963 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 228)
  - April 14, 1984: Hill Country Wine Tour / Campbell-Foreman Building, Livingston / Glider Museum, Terrell / Waverly Plantation, Chappell Hill, 226962 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 229)
  - April 21, 1984: Joe Lagow-Bird Man of Anahauc / Teddy Roosevelt in San Antonio / Galveston Icons / Suehs Mobil Station, Castroville, 226961 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 230)
  - April 28, 1984: Historic Inn Owners, New Braunfels / Sam Houston Remembered / Rattlesnake Bomberbase, Pyote (10-2-76) / Emil Prihoda's Town - Emilville / Dogwood Trail, Palestine, 226960 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 231)
  - May 5, 1984: Ernest Lord-Architect, Navasota / Patillos-Rock Collectors, Robstown / Reuss Drug Store, Cuero / Ross Volunteer-Texas A&M (2-16-80) / Spring Lake Park Hotel, San Marcos, 226959 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 232)
  - June 2, 1984: James Michener Special Segments, 226958 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 236)
  - Sept. 1, 1984: Daylight Trail to Worlds Fair / Emory Rains, Texas Immigrant / Ray Winkelmann's Own Town / Holmes Ed Jones, Oilfield Artist / Jack Glover, Sunset Trading Post, 226957 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 237)
  - Sept. 8, 1984: Odor Detector, Texas A&M / R. Burns-M. LaBarbera, Glass Artists / Jean's (Partin) Tea Room, Baytown / Gov. James Hogg-Papershell Pecan / Swiss Avenue, Dallas, 226956 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 238)
  - Sept. 15, 1984: Model Train Meet, Wimberly / Berthea Ward-Artist, Houston / McClure- McReynolds-Fowler House, Palestine / JW Cox-Vegetable Farmer, Texarkana / Old Jail Museum, Mobeetie, 226955 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 239)
  - Sept. 22, 1984: Madisonville Sidewalk Cattlemen / Grace Episcopal Church, Llano / Jerry Newman-Artist, Beaumont / Parker/Bayview Cemetery, Corpus / Alpine Arboretum, 226954 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 240)
  - Sept. 29, 1984: Blue Grass Festival, Glen Rose / Gulf Building, Houston / Courthouse, Ellis County (3-19-77) / Billy Christopher-Windmills, Monahans / Nuevo Guerro, On Rio Grande, 226953 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 241)
  - Oct. 13, 1984: Credit Union Business / Cook's Fort, Alto / Rowe Valley Dig, Taylor / Felix Harris, Voodoo House / Miles Opera House, 226952 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 243)
  - Oct. 20, 1984: Racing Horses, Laredo / Fuchs House, Horseshoe Bay / Friday Mountain, Driftwood / Harvey Girl, Somerville / Tyler Rose Gardens, 226951 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 244)
  - Oct. 27, 1984: Movie Sets, Marfa & Pflugerville / Pitts & Spitts, Humble / Italian POW Camp, Hereford / Big John Brigham, Plano / Botica Guadalupana Pharmacy, 226950 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 245)
  - Nov. 24, 1984: Czech Newspaper, West / Julius Slaughter-Wood Artist / Wilmer Little & Oxen, Lovelady / Dempsey House, Austin / Ding Dong Daddy, Dumas, 226949 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 249)
  - Dec. 1, 1984: Doris Cantrell-Restorer, New Ulm / Eisenhour-Postcard Collector, Galveston / Dean Cardwell-Fish Artist, Austin / John Larn-Camp Cooper, Putnam Ranch / Sawmill Town, Wiergate, 226948 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 250)
  - Dec. 8, 1984: Hilton Hotel School, Houston / Dabney Log Cabin, Evergreen / First National Bank, Albany / Star Party, Fort Davis, 226947 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 251)
  - Dec. 15, 1984: Larry Baughn-Tumbleweed Collector / Martin Lehnis-RR Man, Early / Joe Smith-Map Collector, Houston / Texas State Cemetery, Austin, 226946 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 252)
  - Dec. 22, 1984: Giorgio Borlenghi-Builder, Houston / Linnville - Texas Ghost Town / Tom O'Carroll-Harnesses, Manvel / Cactus Hotel, San Angelo / Freeman Plantation, Jefferson, 226945 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 253)
- 1985 episodes, 226917
  - KPRC's summary of 1985 episodes, 226943 (Folder 8)
  - Jan. 5, 1985: Bath Houses, Marlin / Old Montgomery Houses / Model T Meet, Hill Country / Sue Holder-Tom Mason - Potters, 226942 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 255)
  - Jan. 12, 1985: Ice Rink Construction, Houston / Ruben Frels-Organ Man, Victoria / Route 66, Potter County / Walling Log Cabin-Arnold Outhouse, 226941 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 256)
  - Jan. 19, 1985: Jim Lemons-GI Cartoonist, Richardson / Texas Zoo, Victoria / Chapel- Horseshoe Bay, Burnet Co. / Packsaddle Hang Gliders, Kingsland (11-22-80) / John Conner Museum, Kingsville, 226940 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 257)
  - Jan. 26, 1985: 20s-30s Basketball Champs, Athens / Bob Platt-Political Buttons, Fort Worth / Alfred Finn-Architect, Houston / San Juan Hotel, San Juan-The Valley, 226939 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 258)
  - Feb. 23, 1985: Indian Creek Church & Cemetery / Million Barrell Oil Tank, Monahans / Walter Reinecker-Sausage Man / Texas Sports Hall of Champions, 226938 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 262)
  - March 2, 1985: Wagner Project, Bastrop / Goodman House, Tyler / Kim Thronsburg, Model Ships / Hallettsville Courthouse, 226937 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 263)
  - March 9, 1985: Oldtime String Shop, Nacogdoches / Bandera Hotel / Al Ross Springstead- Hoofer / Dutchman Shop, Decker Prairie, 226936 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 264)
  - March 16, 1985: Margo Jones Home, Livingston / Johnny Lane-Cowboy Singer, Seguin / B.E. Cruthirds-Cap Collector (5-17-80) / All Faiths Chapel, Austin / Morton Museum, Gainesville, 226935 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 265)
  - March 23, 1985: Kenneth Corder-Seasonings, New Caney / Sugar Land Depot / Texana Museum, Edna / Mule Drawn Tourist Wagon, Jefferson, 226934 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 266)
  - March 30, 1985: Wells Branch Log Cabin, Austin / Cisco Swimming Hole (10-3-81) / Steve Oseychuk-Robots, Houston / Fink's Cigar Band Collector, Houston / Urquharts Castle Inn, Navasota, 226933 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 267)
  - April 6, 1985: Jones Autowerkes, San Antonio / Sisters of Charity, Galveston-Houston / Ruhmann Log Cabin, Frelsburg / Hill House, Harlingen, 226932 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 268)
  - April 13, 1985: Cactus Garden Dilema, Alamo / Helen Smith's Kitchen, Baytown / Primary Primates, Leon Springs / Czech Museum, Temple, 226931 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 269)
  - April 20, 1985: Halley's Comet, Navasota / R.C. Neff-Rug Weaver, New Caney / Simpson Memorbilla Auction, Houston / Castroville Tour, 226930 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 270)
  - Sept. 14, 1985: Buffalo & Burgers, Justiceburg / Bob Spiller-Fishnet Knitter, Freeport / Come & Take It Cannon, Gonzales / Pecos Bill-Alley Theatre, Houston / Dave Stirton-Flies Texas Perimeter, 226929 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 277)
  - Sept. 21, 1985: Gilbert Lamb-Muleshoe Booster / Belle of Beaumont-Paddlewheeler / Martin Rutledge-Burgers, Brownsville / 'Bear' Hollis-Marathon Mule Man (9-20-80) / Lake Meredith, Hutchinson Co., 226928 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 278)
  - Sept. 28, 1985: Indian House/Battleground, Perryton / Linda Long-Pet Photographer, Irving / Eilenberger Bakery, Palestine / Camp Wallace, Hitchcock / Palo Duro & Tule Canyons, 226927 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 279)
  - Oct. 26, 1985: Lone Star Ship, London-Galveston / JA (John Adair) Ranch, Clarendon / Warren & Olete Duren, Mullin / Comal River, New Braunfels, 226926 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 283)
  - Nov. 2, 1985: Crank It Up Contest, Dallas / Mantua-Ghost Town, Collin Co. (5-16-81) / Larry Martin-Stickman, Splendora / Cowboy Breakfast, Palo Duro Canyon / Heritage Square, Austin, 226925 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 284)
  - Nov. 11, 1985: Darrell Lister-Bee Buster, Bellaire / Jones-Cox Country Store, Haskell / Annette Bristol-Tarzan Lady (1-10-81) / Falls of the Brazos, Marlin / Chicken Fried Steak Cookoff, Big Spring, 226924 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 285)
  - Nov. 16, 1985: Sheep Shearing Contest, San Angelo / Ferguston Maps, San Antonio / Cason Monk Funerals, Nacogdoches / Betty & Herb Dean's Hobbies, Weslaco / Billy Bragg- Broadcast Museum (1-2-82), 226923 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 286)
  - Nov. 23, 1985: David McKelzey-Bird Expert, Austin / Kyle Building, Beaumont / W.P. Soash- Soash / Sell Brothers-Big Collectors, Perryton / Studio 205, Victoria (2-27-82), 226922 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 287)
  - Nov. 30, 1985: Bessie & Bill Sauls-Pioneers, Floyd Co. / Old Ingram (2-20-82) / Billie Stout-Chair Maker, Hardin / Hungry Potter Restaurant, Marshall / Tarrant Co. Courthouse, Ft. Worth, 226921 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 288)
  - Dec. 7, 1985: Chuck Stockdale-Airshow Pilot, Pearland / Quilting Bee-Cedar Bayou, Baytown / Gaines-Oliphint House, Milam / Dancing at Laundromat, Azle (12-19-81) / Bob Reinhardt -Collector, Fort Davis, 226920 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 289)
  - Dec. 14, 1985: TJ VanAuken-14-Makes Boudin, Nederland / Doug & Gail Baker- Antiquest, Brenham / Marine Bio Museum, Padre Isl. (10-23-82) / Pictographs, Commanche Creek / Dickens on the Strand, Galveston, 226919 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 290)
  - Dec. 21, 1985: Nancy Ford-Deck the Halls, Houston / Stone Fort Museum, Nacogdoches / Opal Hunt-Store Keeper, Bradshaw / Pompeiian Villa, Port Arthur, 226918 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 291)
- 1986 episodes, 226886
  - KPRC's summary of 1986 episodes, 226916 (Folder 9)
  - Jan. 25, 1986: Sheriff Nathan Tindall, San Augustine / Wedding Chapel, Missouri City / 2 Museums, Crowell / Alsatian Restaurant, Castroville, 226915 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 295)
  - Feb. 1, 1986: World Travel Market, London / Wabbitts Wood Works, Cleveland / Bonnie & Clyde, Dallas / Palestine Texas, 226914 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 296)
  - Feb. 8, 1986: C&W Craze, London & Europe / Main Street Project, Conroe / Bill Jaxon-Artist, Salado (1-24-81) / Spoetzl Brewery, Shiner / Brazos Bend State Park, Needville, 226913 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 297)
  - Feb. 15, 1986: Sesquicentennial Wagon Trail, Livingston / Hilary Page-Artist, Houston / Fandangle-Frontier Celebration, Albany / UT School of Nursing, Galveston / Pride House, Jefferson, 226912 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 298)
  - Feb. 22, 1986: Drew & Susan Patterson-Glass Art, Dripping Springs / Log Stone House, Baytown / Bloor Mansion, Manor / Jean Crain-Bible Class, Nacona / Nave Museum, Victoria, 226911 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 299)
  - March 1, 1986: Washington on the Brazos, 226910 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 300)
  - March 8, 1986: Lamont Bldg/Isabella Ct, Houston / San Felipe, Texas / JR Rowland- United Scale Models, Houston / Liberty Hill Stagestop, 226909 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 301)
  - March 15, 1986: Texas Opera Theater, Abilene / Hearnewood, Hearne / Bradley Bowman- Violin Maker, Bryan / Caldwell Zoo, Tyler, 226908 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 302)
  - March 22, 1986: Bartholomew House, Austin / Joseph Rougely-Basketmaker, Deadwood / San Jacinto Cabin, Deer Park / Wild Mexican Cattle, Laangry (9-18-82) / Bill Gibbs, Old Magnolia, TX, 226907 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 303)
  - March 29, 1986: Dave Stirton Flies Texas. Part 1-Houston to South Padre / Part 2-South Padre to El Paso / Part 3-El Paso to Panhandle / Part 4-Panhandle to Houston, 226906 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 304)
  - April 5, 1986: Shamrock Hilton-Last Party, Houston / Montgomery's Doll Ranch, Rusk / Presidio La Bahia, Goliad / Lucy Mauk-Cactus Collector, Sterling City, 226905 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 305)
  - April 12, 1986: Lightcrust Doughboys, Fort Worth / American Indian Horse Registry, Marshall / Texas Capitol Tour for the Blind / Cal Farley's Boys Ranch, Tascosa (9-26-81) / San Jacinto Battlefield & Park, 226904 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 306)
  - April 19, 1986: San Jacinto Special. San Jacinto Intro / Sam Houston's Trail to Texas / Texas Army / Sequi Wagon Trail School / Battle of San Jacinto, 226903 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 307)
  - April 26, 1986: Mike Shoup-Antique Roses, Independence / XIT Ranch, Panhandle (10-23-82) / Peach Point Preserve / Cow House Fashions, Mt. Pleasant / Barrow Ranch Museum, Eola, 226902 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 308)
  - May 3, 1986: Geo McAlister-Electronic Cowboy, New Braunfels / Crowe's Nest (Pet Shop), Austin / Cotton Seed Oil Mill, Navasota / Elizabeth Crockett (5-23-81), 226901 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 309)
  - May 10, 1986: John Thomas-Wildflower Seeds, Eagle Lake / Norman Morgan-Photo Restorer, Odessa / Meyer Reiswerg-Col. Bubbie's, Galveston / Alibates National Mnt, Panhandle (9-19-82) / Lillie Forson-General Store, Telico, 226900 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 310)
  - May 17, 1986: Flower Ladies of Woodville / Telico - Church Restoration / Hopkins-Rock Collectors, Falls City / Chappell Hill Cemetery / FM 1431 Cedar Park-Kingsland, 226899 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 311)
  - May 24, 1986: WPA Post Office Art / Milton Bullock, Country Writer, Maydelle / Conquista Crossing, Falls City / Temple Beth-El, Corsicana, 226898 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 312)
  - May 31, 1986: Natl Wildflower Research Ctr, Austin / Schroeder-Model RailRoad, Taylor / John Wilkes Booth in Grandbury? / Lorena, TX, 226897 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 313)
  - Sept. 6, 1986: Texas Folklife Festival. Part 1 - Texas Folklife Festival / Part 2 - Texas Folklife Festival / Part 3 - Texas Folklife Festival / Part 4 - Texas Folklife Festival, 226896 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 314)
  - Sept. 13, 1986: Market Square Dig, Houston / Marfa Courthouse, Presidio Co. / Bailey's Well & Windmills, McLean / Panhandle Plains Museum, Canyon, 226895 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 315)
  - Sept. 20, 1986: Elite Cafe & The Circle, Waco / Leo St. Clair-Music Boxes, Sulphur Springs / Barbed Wire Convention, Cuero / Burkburnett-The Man & The Town / Hasse House, Mason, 226894 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 316)
  - Oct. 18, 1986: Weatherford's Gas & Fashion, Hearne / Hardeman Project, Bay City & Madera, CA. / Edison Plaza Museum, Beaumont / Jim Kamas-Renaissance Gardner, Plantersville, 226893 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 320)
  - Oct. 25, 1986: Burro & Mustang Assn, Liberty Hill / Toennies' Home Cannery, Yorktown / Bat Cave, Bracken / Texas Ranger Motel, Santa Anna, 226892 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 321)
  - Nov. 11, 1986: Computer Registration, Texas A&M / Yelderman-Dump King, Damon (12-12-81) / Claiborne Kyle Log House, Kyle / Whitted Family Band, Midland / Station Master House, Spearman, 226891 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 322)
  - Nov. 11, 1986: Starke-Guadalupe River Ranch, Boerne / Melrose Hotel, Dallas / Damian Priour-Sculptor, Florence / Reiffert Mugge House, Cuero, 226890 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 323)
  - Nov. 15, 1986: Fort Chadvourne, Bronte / Downtown Dumas Art, Dumas / John Hardin, Burkburnett / Pioneer Village, Gonzales, 226889 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 324)
  - Nov. 22, 1986: Rock Fences, Mason County / Bordertown Days, Farwell / Hawkins & Bordelon-WWII Heroes / Copper Breaks State Park, Quanah, 226888 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 325)
  - Dec. 20, 1986: SW Black Film Archives, Tyler / Vicker's Inn, La Porte / Larry Pena-Tile Master, San Antonio / Wild Basin Wilderness Preserve, Austin, 226887 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 329)
- 1987 episodes, 226846
  - KPRC's summary of 1987 episodes, 226885 (Folder 10)
  - Jan. 3, 1987: Alexander's Mall-Walkers Store, Luling / Stromberg-Cedar Furniture, Alto / Kosher Tortillas-Monterey House, Houston / Children's Museum, Frederickburg, 226884 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 330)
  - Jan. 10, 1987: Ring Necked Pheasants, Plainview / Floyd Baker-House Mover, Conroe / Kingsbury, Guadalupe County / Lee Family Hummers, Reagan Wells (1-29-83) / Aransas National Wildlife Refuge, 226883 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 331)
  - Jan. 17, 1987: Pace Picante Sauce, San Antonio / Southwestern U - 1936 Reunion / Darragh House, Galveston / Industry Texas, 226882 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 332)